You know about the owner of the brewery,
这个啤酒厂老板的情况
right?
你知道吧
He used to work at
他之前在那个
Dajiang Brewery.
大江啤酒工作过
Later on,
后来呢
he worked for
在奥古特的啤酒厂
August Brewery.
也工作过
Then he quit his job
然后就辞去了工作
and went to Shanghai to pursue his career.
去上海打拼
Now let me give you
我现在跟你介绍一下
some details about that company.
这个公司的情况吧
Hey, I'm talking about work.
我跟你说工作呢
You looked distracted.
干吗心不在焉的
Oh, OK.
拿 拿过来了啊
I brought it...
早拿过
It's flickering again.
又闪
I can't tell if it's the light or
也不知道是灯的问题
the electrical box.
还是电箱的问题
I...
我
really fell for her.
真的喜欢上她了
Again,
又闪
is it the box
也不知道是灯箱还是
or the light?
灯有问题
You've got to find a technician
得 得找个师傅
to take it down
取下来
and fix it.
修一下
That's true.
那也是
I haven't added the detergent yet.
我还没有放洗衣液
That's fine. I'll take care of it.
不用了 那我自己放
Grab the documents and leave.
拿上文件赶紧走吧啊
Still working?
还忙着呢
Have some milk.
喝杯牛奶
Thank you.
谢谢
Are you OK?
还好吗
I should have looked into
其实造船厂的事情
the shipyard case earlier.
我应该提前了解一下
But it's not your concern.
跟你又没关系
Verifying the case is
核实项目这个事情
part of my job.
是我的工作范畴
And you
而且你
have never been in touch with Mr. Yang.
又没有接触过杨总
I've interacted with him several times
我接触过不止一次
but didn't notice
却没发现
anything unusual.
有什么不对的地方
This is still my own issue.
还是我自己的问题
I let myself be led around.
让人牵着鼻子走
Xiaoning,
筱柠
it's not a big deal,
其实一个项目走不下去
if a project can't move forward.
不是什么大事
Let's just take this as
这次我们就当成
a lesson learned.
是一个教训
Next time, you'll be more careful.
下次更谨慎一点就好了
Besides, you've just started handling
况且你也刚刚开始接手
these loan projects.
这些信贷的项目
It's normal to
出点问题
encounter some issues.
也是难免的
But Tang Yuhui
可是唐羽卉
is also new to this.
她也是刚接触啊
Yet she can spot
她就能发现有什么
the problems.
不对的地方
I, however, cannot.
我却不能
I'm not trying to compete with her.
我也不是想跟她比
It's just that
只是
the facts are clear.
事实摆在这儿
I am simply not capable enough.
我的能力也摆在这儿
Tang Yuhui is
唐羽卉她是因为
a unique case.
情况比较特殊吗
Maybe.
也许吧
It's getting late.
太晚了
You should get some rest.
你赶紧回去睡吧
I'm fine.
我没事
Didn't we agree on this?
咱们不是说好了吗
Not to talk about work at home?
在家里不聊工作
Regarding this case,
这次的事情
I just need some time to process it.
我得一个人好好想想
I just need to sort it out.
想明白就好了
Should I reschedule
那要不周末的事情
our weekend plans?
我调整一下
No.
不用
I've already promised mom.
我都答应妈了
I don't want to let her down.
不要让她失望
I won't let her worry either.
我也不会让她担心的
You can rest assured.
你放心好了
Drink it while it's hot.
趁热喝
I'll leave you alone then.
我就不打扰你了
Alright.
好
I don't know what's going on
小涂最近不知道
with Xiaoning lately.
遇到什么事了
She seems to be daydreaming all the time.
没事就发呆
She seems
感觉
to have lost
眼神里都少了
that spark in her eyes.
以前那种灵气了
What does she need that for?
要灵气干什么
To cultivate immortality?
修仙啊
Not like you, floating around
跟你一天似的仙气飘飘
like a fairy all day.
飘来飘去
Don't film me.
你别拍我啊
Come on.
来
Film them.
赶紧拍他们
Today's stars are
今天的主角是
Yuheng and Yuhui.
小纪和小唐
- They're the stars. - Sir.
他们全部是主角 行长
I can feel the vibe.
看您这架势
Could it be that...
难道是
You're the smart one.
就数你最精了
Come on!
来
What are we waiting for?
还愣着干吗呀
A round of applause!
鼓掌
Awesome!
好
So, sir
那行长
when do we expect our bonuses?
咱的奖金什么时候发呀
It'll be yours once the deal is complete.
结算完就发
You won't miss a single cent.
一分都少不了你的
Aside from this,
今天除了这个事之外呢
we will commend
重点是要表扬一下
our fastest rising manager,
咱们这儿最快
Yuhui.
升经理的小唐
She's not only pretty but also talented.
这个小唐呢是秀外慧中
Her future looks promising!
未来可期呀
Keep up the great work.
再接再厉
Now,
那个
since everyone is here
今天大家都没出外勤
and no one is out on duty,
都到齐了
let's take a group photo.
咱们一块拍个合影
Come on!
来
Come on, everyone!
来 来 来
Our section one
咱们拓展一部
hasn't got a group photo yet.
还没有拍过合照呢
Come on.
赶紧地
You join in too!
你也一块啊
Just stand here.
你就站在这儿啊
You're the star today.
你是今天的主角
You should be in front.
往前站
Just stand here, where are you going?
就站这去哪啊
I'm just saying...
咱们就说
It's not right for me to stand here.
我站这不合适
What's wrong with it?
有什么不合适
You're going nowhere.
站这儿别动
Section one!
拓展一部
Let's go!
业绩长虹
Come on!
来
Three.
三
Two.
二
One.
一
Shall we take another one?
还需要再拍一张吗
Let's take another one.
再来一张 再来一张
Come on, come on!
来 来 来
Section one!
拓展一部
Let's go!
业绩长虹
About what I mentioned in the chat.
我在群里说的那个
Xu Li.
许力
Regarding the company's qualifications.
公司的资质
Please take this contract back,
你把这份合同拿回去
- and make some revisions. - Guys.
再改一改 收拾 收拾
Let's call it a day.
下班吧
Mr. Ji,
纪总
it's rare that everyone is here today,
今天难得大家人这么齐
and there's good news as well.
而且又有喜事
Let's all get together!
咱们一块聚一聚吧
Yuhui,
小唐
if you want to treat us,
你这么想请客的话
I have a place in mind.
姐给你推荐一个地方
It's perfect for drinking,
特别适合喝酒
but it's pricey.
就是人均消费有点高
Should I
我要不要提前
make a reservation now?
帮你订位子啊
Sure!
可以啊
Alright.
行
Then I'll make the reservation.
那我订位子
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐
you're coming, right?
你也去的吧
I still have work to do.
我还有工作没做完
You all go ahead.
你们去吧我就不去了
Alright.
行
Don't
那
work too hard.
别太晚啊
You'd better
我劝你
cut down on alcohol.
还是少喝点酒
Or I'll have to clean up your mess again.
免得我又要给你擦屁股
I'm just saying,
我劝你呀
be careful with your words.
说话注意点
What?
不是怎么着
Are you really in love with me?
真爱上我了呀
Speaking of that,
你说起这个吧
I just remembered
我突然想起来
I forgot my ID.
工牌没拿
Out of my face!
滚
Boss,
领导
you really need to...
你今天真的
You've got to tag along.
你得去
You must go.
你必须得去
After all this time, you...
这么长时间你每次
Besides,
再说了
this time it's Yuhui who invited you.
这次是小唐叫您
You have to go, no matter what.
说什么都得去
Just go, shall we?
去吧 去吧 去吧
I can't even do my work properly.
我工作都工作不好了
Really.
真的
This time you must come with us.
这次你必须得跟我们去
If you don't go,
你不去
it's just not right.
太说不过去了
Come on, come on!
走 走 走
Mr. Ji, we've been so busy with work,
纪总咱们工作这么忙
right?
对不对
We've finally got a chance to
咱们哪有时间去
get together and build our relationships.
沟通下感情啊
Let's have a drink for this.
咱们就趁着这个喝酒
Yuhui, I've already made the reservation.
小唐位置我订好了啊
Oh,
对了
I just remembered
我突然想到
there's an email I still need to send.
有一个邮件还没发
I need to take care of it first.
我先去处理一下
I'll wait for you.
那 那我等你
No problem.
没关系
You all go ahead.
你们先去
Alright, Mr. Ji, see you later.
好纪总一会儿见
Take your time.
不着急
OK, later.
好 拜拜
Hey.
干吗
We're still in the office.
在公司呢
Someone might see us.
被人看见
There's no one around.
没有人了
Are you alright?
还好吗
I'm OK.
还好
I'm just a bit tired.
我就是有点累了
I don't really feel like going out.
不太想出去玩
Then let's just head home.
那咱们就回家
We can order some beer,
点点儿啤酒
get some fried chicken,
点点儿炸鸡
and watch a movie.
看个电影
If you have anything to ask or vent about,
有什么想问的想吐槽的
just share with me.
都可以跟我说
I don't have anything to vent about.
我没有什么想吐槽的
I failed on the project.
项目失败了
It's a reflection of my abilities.
确实是我能力的问题
I acknowledge that.
我认
You should go have fun with them.
你赶紧陪他们去玩吧
Being top in performance
业绩第一
is a recognition of your hard work.
是对你工作的肯定
You really should go.
不去不好
But I don't want to
但是我也不想
see you like this.
看到你这样
You failed once.
这只是一次失败
You must not
千万不要就这样
doubt yourself like this.
轻易地否定自己
It's not just one time.
哪是一次
It's happened many times.
好多次了
But that's OK.
不过没关系
I'm going shopping
我跟凌惟依
with Ling Weiyi later.
一会儿出去逛街
We'll spend some money
多花点钱
on some happiness.
买快乐去
After all, I have
反正纪总的卡
Mr. Ji's credit card.
在我这儿
Spend as much as you like.
随便花
I don't even need to know.
我连知情权都不需要有
Just don't come home too late.
别回来太晚啊
Be careful.
注意安全
Don't worry.
放心吧
Tomorrow we still have
明天不是还要
to visit dad's grave, right?
给爸爸扫墓去吗
You should come home early.
你也早点回来
OK.
早点回
Off you go.
快走吧
Go.
走吧
Later.
拜拜
- Let's go. - Why aren't you buying?
走吧 你为什么不要啊
No need to buy them.
不要买了
A pair won't amuse you for a month.
一双开心不了一个月
Maybe a week.
能开心一个礼拜吧
Three pairs might last twenty days.
三双能开心二十天了
Don't spend that much on boots.
少花点钱吧
I still need to
我还是要稍微
remind you.
提醒你一下
You're with Qi Yu now,
你现在跟齐郁在一起
so you shouldn't spend that much.
要省着点花
You still need to
你还是要适当地
consider the feelings of us
照顾一下我们这种
ordinary folks, alright?
平头百姓的感受吗
I did.
我照顾了呀
I go out with him and
我跟他一块
I always take care of the bills secretly.
我都是自己偷偷结账的
One sec.
等一会
Hello?
喂
Aquarium?
水族馆
What?
干吗
I was thinking of
我还想着跟筱柠
having dinner with Xiaoning.
一块吃晚饭呢
Why don't you come over?
要不你过来
Alright then.
那行吧
Wait for me.
你等我一会儿
I'll be there soon.
我马上就过来
He wanted me to go to
你突然说什么
the aquarium all of a sudden.
要约我去水族馆
Go ahead, eat by yourself.
那你就自己吃
I'll treat you another day.
改天我再请你吃好吃的
OK.
好
Let me know when you get there.
你到了告诉我一声
Be safe on your way back.
你回去注意安全
See ya.
拜拜
Weiyi,
惟依
my results are out.
我的考试成绩出来了
Did you pass it?
过了
You passed it, Qi Yu!
你考过了齐郁
You really passed it!
真的假的
That's amazing, Qi Yu!
太棒了齐郁
I'm so happy for you!
我太为你感到高兴了
I must get you a gift.
我一定要给你送个礼物
What should I get you?
送什么呢 送什么
Let me see.
我想一下
How about a
要不给你送个
motorcycle?
摩托车
A watch?
手表
Or maybe I can get you something you like,
要不给你送你喜欢的
like that
那张伯伦的
Chamberlain's personal basketball?
御用篮球怎么样
I don't need any of those.
都不用
Then what do you want?
那你要什么
Weiyi,
惟依
sunrise, starry sky, sunset.
日出 星空 落日
I like all the things you like.
你喜欢的我都喜欢
I want to watch them with you forever.
我想陪你看一辈子
Once I secure the job,
等我工作落定后
let's go watch the sunrise together.
我们一起去看日出吧
Is this
你不会是
your proposal?
想要跟我求婚吧
I might not say yes.
那我可不一定答应
It depends on my mood.
看心情吧
Thank you for bringing me here.
谢谢你带我来这儿
Today is
今天呢
a wonderful day for you.
是你大好的日子
Let's take a photo in here.
我们在这儿合影吧
Come on,
快
let's record this moment of joy.
打卡记录一下
Yay!
耶
You're up.
起来了
Where did you go early in the morning?
一大早你干吗去了
I went for a jog.
跑步去
The physical fitness test for police has
这几年的警察体能考核
become much stricter in recent years.
严格了很多
I need to train harder.
我得加紧训练
I have to take it seriously.
不能马虎
You sit
你说你上班
at work every day.
每天都坐着
Let's go workout together.
要不要一起运动一下
I'm not going!
我才不去呢
Then I'm heading out.
那我出门了
You just sleep in.
你再睡一会
I'm hungry.
我肚子饿了
Can you make some breakfast for me?
你帮我做早饭好不好
Alright.
好了
Stop fooling around.
别闹了
Wait for me to come back.
等我回来啊
I'll bring you breakfast.
回来给你带早饭
OK.
行吧
I'm off!
去了啊
Fruits.
水果
You're up.
你醒了
Just in time.
正好过来
See what I might have missed.
帮我想想有什么没带的
I've prepared liquor,
我准备了酒
fruits, and pastries.
水果 糕点
And then...
然后
I forgot flowers!
花忘买了
No need to worry.
不用紧张
I bought flowers
花昨天晚上
last night.
我已经买好了
They're in the trunk.
放在了后备箱里
That won't do.
不行
Mom said dad likes sunflowers.
妈说爸爸喜欢向日葵
I have to get sunflowers.
我得去买向日葵
That's exactly what I got.
买的就是向日葵
No need to worry.
不用担心
Really?
真的
Why are you so good?
你怎么这么好呀
If you didn't get them for me,
要不然
it would be so messed up.
我就要食言了
I promised mom already.
我都答应妈妈的
Why am I so good?
我怎么这么好
Even though I'm this good,
就算我这么好
someone still not wants
有些人有心事
to tell me what's on her mind.
不还是不告诉我吗
Hold still.
别动
Let me recharge.
我抱着充会电
To be honest,
说实话
the shipyard case
造船厂的事情
and
还有
Tang Yuhui getting promoted to
唐羽卉先我一步
account manager ahead of me
转正当客户经理的事
has really hit me hard.
对我打击还是挺大的
I might need some time
我可能需要一些时间
to process all these.
慢慢才能缓过来
I don't even know why
我也不知道为什么
these things
这些事情
made me feel
让我觉得
so lacking in confidence right now.
现在特别没有自信
I've been overshadowed by negativities.
一直被负面情绪笼罩着
But I believe I'll be OK.
但我相信我会好的
Don't
你
you
你不许
look down on me.
瞧不起我
You must not make fun of me either.
不许笑话我
Come on,
抱抱
how could I do that to you?
我怎么会笑话你呢
I just want to help you.
我是想帮你
But I just
只是我也不知道
don't know how.
究竟该如何帮好
I'd love to support you
我想帮着你
in regaining
赶快找回那个
your confidence,
无所畏惧的涂筱柠
so you could stop feeling down like this.
而不是现在这样
I understand.
我知道
It's dad.
爸的电话
OK,
好
I'll pack the stuff.
我收拾东西
Hello, dad.
喂 爸
Dad, mom!
爸 妈
You're here.
你们来了
What happened?
怎么回事啊
They're operating on her now.
正在里面抢救呢
Last night, she went to bed
昨天晚上亲家母啊
earlier than usual.
睡得比往常都要早
We thought
我们就以为
she wanted to get up early this morning
她是想今天早上早起
to wait for you to pick her up.
等着你们过来接她
You planned to go to the cemetery, right?
不是去扫墓吗
So we didn't think much of it.
我们就没当回事
But when we got up this morning,
结果早上起来以后
not long after,
没一会儿
she fainted.
她人就晕倒了
It was my fault.
都是我没照顾好
I should have
我应该
been more attentive.
再仔细一点就好了
Mom,
妈
don't say that.
您别这么说
You got her here in time.
这不是及时送过来了吗
Doctor,
大夫
how is my mom doing?
我妈情况怎么样了
Come to my office.
去我办公室
I'll explain everything to you.
详细跟你们说
Let's go.
走吧
OK.
好
I'm going.
那我先去
Your mother's cancer cells
你母亲的癌细胞
have spread significantly.
扩散很严重
Based on the current symptoms,
根据目前的症状分析
they have started to spread to the brain.
已经开始向脑部转移
The exact extent of the spread
具体的转移程度
will be determined after the test results
要等检查结果
are available.
出来了再说
You have to prepare for the worst.
你们要做好心理准备
The patient isn't likely
病人很有可能
to last much longer.
坚持不了太久
Doctor.
医生
How long does she have left?
是还能有多久啊
Optimistically,
乐观的话
she has about one to two months.
一到两个月
Then,
那
can we switch
我们再换
to other chemotherapy medications?
其他的化疗药物可以吗
Starting radiation and chemotherapy now
现在再来做放化疗
won't do much good.
效果不会太好
Moreover,
再说了
her condition
病人的身体
is not good enough for those.
也不支持
Doctor Zhao,
赵医生
please,
我拜托您
please figure
麻烦您再想想
something out.
其他的办法
No matter how much it costs,
无论我花多少钱
no matter what it takes,
无论我做什么
I will cooperate fully.
我都会配合您
We will do our utmost.
我们尽力
Xiaoning,
筱柠
take these.
这个带着
These are some meds mom often takes.
这些是妈常吃的一些药
Tomorrow, when you're at the hospital,
明天去了医院
just check with the doctor
问一下大夫
which ones can be discontinued
哪些可以停了
and which ones should be kept going.
哪些可以继续用
Aren't you going?
你不去吗
I have to go to Jinghai tomorrow.
我明天要出差去京海
It's regarding the loan for Zhouyang Hotel.
洲洋酒店贷款的事
I've already been in touch with the
我已经跟他们总部的
financial manager at their headquarters.
财务负责人联系上了
Zhouyang?
洲洋
Wasn't that case assigned to section two?
不是分给二部了吗
Yes.
是
But they couldn't finalize the deal.
但是二部那边谈不下来
I happen to have some connections.
我正好有一些门路
You're aiming to secure Zhouyang.
想拿下洲洋
It won't be easy, though.
肯定没那么容易
At the moment,
现在
many banks are vying for it.
很多家银行都在抢
If you get involved with it,
你要是一头扎进去
you'll likely be
肯定很长时间
tied up for a long time.
都脱不开身
Mom will be transferred out of ICU tomorrow.
妈明天从重症转出来
The one she wants to see the most is you.
肯定最想见的人就是你
In my view,
我觉得你这段时间
you'd better spend more time with her.
最好还是多陪陪她
I went to the hospital today.
我今天去了一趟医院
The doctor told me that
医生跟我说
there was a special medicine abroad.
国外有一种特效药
Maybe it's effective for her.
或许能有用
But the cost of treatment
但是一年下来
needs up to 800,000 RMB a year.
治疗的费用需要八十万
I have to make more money as soon as possible.
所以我得加速赚钱了
Can you come back before dinner?
晚饭前能回来吗
I have to dine out with clients tonight.
今晚有饭局要应酬
Come back after midnight.
要凌晨才能到
Door open.
已开锁
Door locked.
已关锁
It's good.
没什么问题
Tell Rao Jing
直接让饶静
to take charge of it.
去负责对接就好
OK.
好
Mom...
妈
she missed you,
她这几天挺想你的
and often talked about you these days.
一直念叨你呢
Don't drink coffee anymore.
少喝点咖啡吧
You've had three cups already.
你今天都喝第四杯了
Don't worry.
放心吧
I refresh myself with it.
提提神
I promise you this is the last one.
最后一杯我保证
You lost flesh
我看你这两天
these days,
都瘦了一大圈了
and have quite black circles.
黑眼圈还挺重的
You can't be like this anymore.
你不能这么熬着
It's bad for your health.
你这样对身体不好
Come in.
进
Director Ji,
纪总
Hello, Xiaoning.
筱柠姐也在
What's up?
找我有事吗
Brother,
师哥
I heard your mom was in hospital.
我听说阿姨病了
Could you tell me which hospital?
在哪家医院啊
I can ask my friends
我 找找朋友
to help
或许能帮得上忙
to take care of her.
多照顾一下
Thank you for your concern.
不用麻烦了
I've got everything arranged.
我都已经安排好了
So...
那
I'd better
我买点礼物过去
buy some gifts for her.
这也是应该的
I appreciate your kindness.
你的好意我心领了
But her medical condition is not good.
我妈最近的状态不太好
The doctor said she needed a quiet environment.
医生说需要静养
You're responsible
另外你手上还有几个
for several clients.
在跟的客户
I hope you can make some progress
下周例会
until the regular meeting next week.
我希望你能有新的进展
So I'm leaving, sir.
那纪总我先出去了
The project will be
那个项目
formally examined and approved
下周就可以
next week.
进行正式的审批了
Good.
好
So...
那
that's it.
我就先不打扰你了
OK.
好
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐
I'll give you
我待会儿给你几个
some clients' information.
客户的资料
You need to compile it into a report presented at the meeting.
你要做一下上会的材料
By the way,
对了
you need to finish it tonight.
今天晚上睡觉前要给我
Me?
我做
Why?
为什么
You assist Jing in doing the project, too.
你不是也帮静姐做吗
She's the manager.
她是经理
So am I now.
我现在也是经理
As an assistant,
你作为助理
that's your job.
不就应该做这些工作吗
I suppose you might be wrong.
经理跟经理不一样
Jing is my master.
静姐是我师父
I should
为她做什么
obey her instructions.
都是我分内的事
But I don't need to
但我没有这个义务
obey yours.
为你做这些
Didn't you hear
可是你刚刚没有
what brother said?
听到师哥说吗
He said
他说我现在的重心
I should focus on the project.
要放在重点项目
I heard it.
听到了
Then do it.
你好好做
I have faith in you.
加油啊
Well done.
干得漂亮
She served that
对于她这种人
right.
就是一点面子都不要留
Tomorrow I'll tell the property company
明天我就让物业后台
to demagnetize her time card.
把她的卡消磁了
I guarantee you that
保证让她
she'll be late for over an hour.
迟到一个小时以上
Don't do that.
你别瞎搞啊
I can deal with her.
我自己能应付得过来
I don't like
我就是看不惯
her arrogance.
她那副样子
In fact,
其实
she's good at dealing with clients.
她也挺厉害的
She drew tens of millions of deposits,
千万级别的存款
and made lending to big business.
大企业的贷款
She did very well.
说拿下来就拿下来
As for me,
我呢
I even couldn't
一个造船厂的老板
see through
有问题
a shipyard owner's trick.
我都看不出来
I thought
反而还傻傻地觉得
I could make a deal with that man.
肯定能行
He hid his real purpose from you.
人家存心要瞒着你
It's reasonable that
你又没开天眼
you didn't know
那你当然不知道
what went wrong.
问题在哪儿
The past is past.
况且这事都已经过去了
Don't let it keep haunting you.
你可千万别再内耗了啊
I got it.
我知道
I'm just at a loss.
我就是觉得有点茫然
When I worked in the bank lobby,
以前在大堂的时候吧
there was a lot of trivial work to do.
工作琐碎
The salary was low.
工资低
I had to deal with rude clients
蛮横不讲理的客户
everyday.
是天天有
Sometimes
有时候
I was pushed into a corner.
有理最后都变成没理了
Then I went to the Business Development Department.
后来呢去了拓展部
I was anxious about getting my permanent employeeship,
为转正焦虑
and about performance.
为业绩焦虑
I was even overwhelmed
任务指数
by the task index.
数不过来
Like me,
很多同事跟我都一样啊
a lot of colleagues were so anxious that
焦虑到
they suffered from insomnia and alopecia.
失眠 脱发
I thought
而且还觉得
the effort was not
为工作付出的跟得到的
proportional to the return.
不成正比
But it's what it is.
其实银行就是这样
The bank is like a Fortress Besieged.
银行就像是一座围城
Outsiders reckon
外面的人觉得
working in it is decent.
光鲜亮丽
However,
其实呢
quite the opposite
里面的人才知道
is true.
到底有多辛苦
I have been working there for four years.
我在这个围城里四年了
I didn't see my bright future ahead.
一点阳光没见着
I've
我也不知道
lost my way
接下来的路
to the future.
该往哪儿走
You are right.
确实是那么个事
But Ji Yuheng
但是你是不是
came into your life.
也遇到了纪昱恒啊
It offsets your career predicament.
这就叫东边不亮西边亮
There always exists a natural balance
能量啊
between good and bad.
它永远都是守恒的
Yes.
是
He was very busy lately.
最近他也挺忙的
He worked hard to make money
忙着赚钱
to afford the special medicine.
给妈换那个特效药
But
但是
I had asked the doctor about it.
我实际上问了医生了
He said
医生说那个药用上了
it was not so effective for her.
可能效果也不会很大
Did he know that?
那他自己知道这事吗
I'm sure
他照顾妈那么久
he did.
怎么会不知道呢
I know
只是人
what he thought.
有时候就是会这样
Even though
他在某一件事情上
the medicine couldn't cure his mom,
无能为力了
he would rather
就想找个地方
have a try.
躲一躲
I can do nothing
我现在能做的呢
for him
就是帮他照顾好妈
except
其他的
taking care of mom.
我什么都做不了
But you should
那你每天也得
take care of yourself well.
好好吃饭啊
You lost weight these days.
我这两天见你都瘦了
I'll order you a take-out
一会儿我就点你
you like best
最爱的外卖
and deliver it to the hospital.
到医院去给你吃
Thank you.
好
I'm sorry.
不好意思 不好意思
I'm so careless.
是我大意了
That's all right.
没事 没事
Ms Cai,
蔡姐啊
you have been here for the whole day.
你也照顾我一天了
You'd better get some rest.
去歇歇吧
Ms Cai,
蔡姐
have some rest.
您去休息吧
I'll take care of her.
这儿交给我
OK.
好
Thank you.
辛苦了
It's OK.
没事
Mom.
妈 我来了
How you doing?
怎么样呀
Did she make you hurt?
弄疼了
She's a good daughter-in-law
多好的儿媳妇呀
who cares about you so much.
比女儿还要亲
Are you hungry?
饿不饿
My mom cooked some fish soup,
我妈今天熬的鱼汤
which is warmed
一直放在
in the canteen.
医院的食堂里温着
I'll get it for you.
我给你拿去
No, thank you.
先不用了
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
Ms Cai can take care of me.
我这里有护工照顾
Your mom often visited me.
你妈妈又经常过来看我
Don't worry about me.
你们都不要担心啊
Tell my son that
尤其要告诉昱恒
I'm OK.
让他不要着急
He doesn't feel at ease.
他能不着急吗
He's worried about you every day.
你儿子天天惦记着你
But
就是
he has been tied up in
他最近银行的事情
business.
实在是太多了
He couldn't spare time for you.
他抽不开身
So don't blame him.
您可不许生他气啊
I won't.
不会 不会
I understand that.
他忙点好啊
What's more,
再说
I don't want him
我也不想他
to see me like this.
看到我现在这个样子
I'm worried
我怕
he would be more upset than I am.
他会比我更难过
Mom,
妈
I need to take the phone call.
我接个电话去
OK, go ahead.
好 去吧
Keep warm.
被子盖好啊
Hello, Fanggang.
喂 小赵哥
What's up?
怎么了
It's the client of the garden area
就是园区的客户
you got in touch with.
之前你也联系过
He has a good impression on you.
人家对你印象不错
He agreed to let you take on the project.
同意让你接过去做
Thank you for telling me this.
谢谢你啊小赵哥
Are you all right?
怎么
You didn't sound excited.
听你兴致不高啊
I'm pleased.
没有
OK.
那就行
I'm going to send you the details.
我把资料发给你
You'd better look it through
你抓紧看
as soon as possible.
看得差不多了
Then I will arrange a client meeting for you.
我帮你约客户见面
OK.
好
Bye-bye.
拜拜
You have to
这个项目
give up the project.
别再跟了
Mr. Yang had been in jail.
杨总他之前进去过
He has a criminal record.
他有案底
It was rumored that
所以之前一直都有传言
he didn't want to take out a loan.
说杨总不贷款
That's not true.
并不代表着他不愿意贷
He was banned from doing that.
而是他贷不了
As a customer manager,
咱们做客户经理的
if we don't have
要是连这点
such occupational sensitivity,
职业敏感度都没有的话
we are
那可能确实
incapable of this job.
不太适合这一行
So
所以
you need to develop other projects.
抓紧时间找其他的项目
Cheer up!
别灰心啊
Door open.
已开锁
Why didn't you sleep?
怎么还没睡呢
I'm looking up some information,
查点资料
and waiting for you.
也是在等你
Go to bed now.
早点睡吧
I want to talk to you.
我想要跟你聊聊
I'm a little tired.
我现在有点累了
We can talk another day.
改天吧
No.
不
That's why I'm waiting for you.
我一直等到你现在呢
We have to talk now.
就今天聊
Let go of me.
你 你先放开
Don't...
别动了
I want a recharge.
让我也充会儿电吧
Why did you give up the project?
为什么不接
Do you have new clients?
你有新的客户了
No.
没有
I don't have much experience.
我本来就没有什么经验
So
暂时
I gave it up.
还是算了吧
But you can accumulate experience
经验都是
step by step.
可以慢慢累积的
If you have any difficulty,
你有拿不准的地方
Jing and I
我跟你静姐
can help you.
都可以帮你的
I get it, Fanggang.
我知道小赵哥
I...
我
Someone in my family
我们家
is in hospital.
有人生病了
I have to take care of her.
我得去照顾
So
就
I can't spare extra time and energy
两边顾不上
for the project.
顾不过来呀
That's why
所以就
I can't take on the project.
还是算了吧
But thank you all the same.
谢谢你啊小赵哥
I need to make a phone call.
我打个电话去
What happened?
怎么了这是
Xiaoning needs performance to a get permanent employeeship.
小涂不是缺客户转正吗
I wanted to introduce a client to her.
我这边正好有一个
Did she decline it?
她不接
She said
她说
her family member
她家里面人生病了
was in hospital
住院
and needed to be taken care of.
需要人照顾
I understand that.
我也能理解
Xiaoning is smart
小涂能力好
and works hard.
又能吃苦
This is a chance for her.
我觉得这是个机会
I'll talk to her
回头
again.
我再找她谈谈吧
Tang told me that
我听小唐说
someone in your family
好像
was in hospital.
你家人也住院了
It's my mom.
是我妈
Her medical condition is not good.
情况也不太乐观
It's all right.
没事
Let's go.
走吧
I got some coffee at a discount.
楼下打折
Buy one, and get one for free.
买一送一
I picked them out at random.
我随便挑的
Manager Zhao,
赵经理
could you not talk with me
你能别用后脑勺
face to back?
跟我讲话吗
OK.
好
It's my favorite flavor.
这个完全符合我的口味
Is it for free?
免费送的
You don't like it?
不想喝
Take it away.
拿走
Try it.
尝尝吧
I'm scared.
害怕
Scared of what?
怕什么呀
Claim an interest from me.
我怕又给我加利息
Neither you nor Xiaoning
你跟小涂
accepted my help.
还真是亲师徒啊
She declined my client offer.
我给小涂客户她不要
You refused my coffee.
给你咖啡你也不要
Both of you failed me.
真是不识好人心
Did you give her a client?
你给她客户了
What's wrong?
怎么了
We worked
我们是不是
from the grounds.
都从底层干起来的
She worked in the bank lobby for three years.
小涂在大堂干了三年
and failed to get the permanent employeeship.
没转正
The effort didn't pay off.
天道不酬勤
Then she was transferred here.
后来来到咱们拓展部
She intended to start from scratch.
想着从头再来
Unexpectedly,
谁能想到
she competed with her old rival,
遇到自己的老对手
and hasn't taken the permanent employeeship yet.
而且到现在都没转正
Now
她现在正是
she's suspicious of
对自己的职业
her career
还有对于她个人
and capacity.
产生怀疑的时候
It's out of your kindness
你现在给她客户
to help her.
你有信心给
But she didn't think about it that way.
她有信心接吗
You just hit her confidence,
你简直就是在打击她
don't you?
你知道吗
I thought
我还以为
you didn't care about her
你一直对
at all.
你这个徒弟不闻不问
I didn't expect
原来饶经理是
you knew her so much.
外冷内热
I did.
你才知道啊
I know everything.
我细心着呢
Do you mind
那什么时候
warmth to me?
对我也热一下
What did you say?
你说什么
I said
我说
your
你什么时候
warmth to me.
对我也热一下
That would get you in trouble.
你不怕引火烧身啊
Anything else?
还有事吗
I...
我是
I have something
我来是跟你
to tell you.
商量一个事情
The director's mom is in hospital.
就是领导的妈妈生病了
So I plan to
所以我想这个
gather colleagues
组织大家去
to visit her.
探望一下
I heard
我知道这事
his mother was sick.
我也听说了
I agree with you.
那你就组织呗
I'm certain
咱赵经理平时
everybody will
不是挺有号召能力的吗
respond to
办公室有点什么事
your call.
一呼百应啊
You don't have to
就这点事
talk about it with me,
有必要找我商量吗
right?
是吧
Fanggang,
哥
why did you always
你为什么一有什么事
tell Jing everything first?
就先跟静姐汇报啊
Manager Zhao,
赵经理
what are you thinking of?
想什么呢
Nothing.
没什么的
So
这
I get the coffee.
咖啡我拿走了啊
It can be the payoff
就算我对你
of the consultation.
答疑解惑的费用吧
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Where are you going?
你去哪儿啊
None of your business.
要你管
Who is it?
干什么的
You again!
怎么又是你啊
I told you
不是跟你说过了吗
it's not the visiting period.
过了探视时间进不去
Get out of here.
回吧 回吧 回吧
Come early next time.
下回早点来
I don't go in.
我不上去
I just stay here for a while.
就站一会儿
Did you have alcohol?
你是不是喝酒了
You'd better not go crazy here.
不是来醉酒闹事的吧
I'll leave in a few minutes.
我站一会儿就走了
Thank you.
麻烦了
Mom,
妈
it has been almost ten years.
快十年了
It's not easy for us
我们好不容易
to have an intact family.
又有了一个完整的家
I don't want to lose it.
上天又要收回吗
Please, give me more time.
求您再多给我一点时间
Door open.
已开锁
Why didn't you go to bed?
还没睡啊
Did you drink again?
你又喝酒了
The financial representatives of Zhouyang
洲洋的财务代表
came here to inspect business.
正好来星城考察
It was a rare chance to dine with them.
他们平时很难约
So
这顿酒
I had to drink with them.
必须得去
Mom is
妈
missing you very much.
很想你
She hadn't seen you
她已经
for a week.
一个星期没见你了
But she didn't
只不过
tell me.
她一直忍着不说
I don't want to talk about it now.
我现在不想说这个事
Why didn't you
你为什么
go to her?
不能去看看她呀
You can't avoid the reality.
你总要面对的不是吗
So you think
所以你觉得
I don't want to face it.
我是不敢面对
Mom is in critical condition.
妈现在一直都不清醒
It doesn't help
就算是我去了
even if I go to visit her.
又能怎么样
I need to earn more money
我还不如多挣点钱
to let her
让那个特效药
take the special medicine.
让她持续能用上
She needs you
她现在需要的不只是药
more than the special medicine.
是你
Can you
你能不能在她
stay with her more
仅有的几个月时间里
in her last few months?
多陪陪她
Don't make yourself regret about it.
也不给自己留遗憾
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
what do you mean?
什么叫几个月的时间
I won't
我不会让她的生命
let her die.
只剩几个月
I'll keep her alive.
我会留住她
Don't lie to yourself.
纪昱恒你在逃避问题
You hate to face mom's medical condition
你不敢面对妈的病情
and the worst outcome.
你不敢面对最坏的结果
You just
每天拿着
escape from reality
出去赚钱买药当幌子
everyday.
却找不到人
In fact,
其实呢
you just make excuses for yourself.
你就是在给自己找借口
Yes,
对
you're right.
我是在逃避
But what about you?
那你呢
Zhao Fanggang intended to introduce a client to you.
赵方刚给你介绍的客户
Why did you refuse him?
为什么不接
You failed to deal with the project of the shipyard,
造船厂的项目黄了
then you
你就不相信自己
lost confidence,
怀疑自己的能力
right?
不是吗
You'd better
还是把自己的事情
mind your own business first.
管好再说吧
So you don't mind
所以一直当助理
being an assistant,
也没关系
and failing to pass the assessment
转正考核
of permanent employeeship.
不通过也没关系
I don't mind.
没关系
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
Don't bring your bad mood back home.
还是别把情绪带回去了
She's under a lot of pressure, too.
她的压力也很大
Door open.
已开锁
Why didn't you sleep?
怎么还没睡呢
I'm looking up some information,
查点资料
and waiting for you.
也是在等你
Go to bed now.
早点睡吧
I want to talk to you.
我想要跟你聊聊
I'm a little tired.
我现在有点累了
We can talk another day.
改天吧
No.
不
That's why I'm waiting for you.
我一直等到你现在呢
We have to talk now.
就今天聊
Let go of me.
你先放开
Don't...
别动了
I want a recharge.
让我也充会儿电吧